A Guide to the David Rockefeller papers, Associates, Joseph Jennen FA1236
Rockefeller Archive Center
David Rockefeller papers, Associates, Joseph Jennen
1946-1973
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, David (1915-2017)
Jennen, Joseph
Dana, Richard
FA1236
8.03 Cubic Feet 10 letter document boxes and 9 legal document boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research in accordance with the terms of donation from the David Rockefeller estate (January 2019). Brittle or damaged material is available at the discretion of the Rockefeller Archive Center.
Scope and Contents
The Joseph Jennen papers document David Rockefeller investments and the investments of other Rockefeller family memebers in the Congo and Venezuela in the 1940s-1950s. The collection also contains files created by Richard Dana and Jennen documenting the purchase, sale and management of David Rockefeller's properties in St. Barts. Also included are select Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600) quarterly reports and Reports to Directors.
Records are predominantly in English, with many in French.
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
- Joseph Jennen and Richard Dana Files, 1958-1973; 1; 2.66 Cubic Feet 7 letter document boxes
  - St. Barts - General Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - St. Barts - General Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - St. Barts - General Correspondence, 1964-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
  - St. Barts - Guests, 1962-1973 (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
  - St. Barts - Guest House - Costs, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - St. Barts - Hurricane, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - St. Barts - Orders, 1959-1970 (Box 4, Folder 8-10, Box 5, Folder 1-8, Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - St. Barts - Philippe Claude Hotel Project, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - St. Barts - Properties, 1958-1970 (Box 6, Folder 6-12, Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    Scope and Contents
    Purchases and sales.
  - St. Barts - Roof - New, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Joseph Jennen Investment Files, 1940-1960; 2; 5.67 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes and 9 legal document boxes
  - Dillon Reed and Co. Inc - Belgian Congo, 1956-1958 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Indussa Corporation, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Belgian Congo Investment Fund, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Nuclear Development Corporation, 1957-1960 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Anacongo, 1950-1956 (Box 8, Folder 2-4, Box 9, Folder 1-5)
  - Belgian Congo Investment Fund, 1955-1959 (Box 9, Folder 6-7, Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - Bamoco, 1955-1959 (Box 10, Folder 4-6)
  - CEGEAC, 1952-1959 (Box 11, Folder 1-6)
    Aviation in the Congo.
  - CEGEAC, 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
  - Vertol-Sabena, 1958-1960 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Cimenterie Stanleyville, 1956-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - COBEGA, 1956-1957 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Cuvette Congolaise, 1956-1957 (Box 13, Folder 5, Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Filtisaf - James Baldwin, 1955-1960 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Filtisaf - Thomas Bancroft, 1955-1960 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Filtisaf - W. A. and A. M. White, 1951-1955 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Filtisaf - Price Waterhouse Reports, 1946-1959 (Box 14, Folder 5-6, Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Filtisaf - Certificate of Inscription, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Filtisaf - Building Plans (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Filtisaf - Common Stock (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Belgian Congo Textile Project, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Investments in Belgium - Transfer to US Dollar, 1940s (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Filtisaf - Financial, 1950-1953 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Filtisaf - First Reimbursement - Second Bond Issue, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Filtisaf - Director's Fees, 1950-1960 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Filtisaf - Interest Payment Filtisaf Bonds, 1952-1956 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Filtisaf - Financial - Financial, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Filtisaf - Financial - First Bond Issue and New Shares, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Filtisaf - Financial - Second Bond Issue, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Filtisaf - Financial - Transfer of Stock, 1947-1951 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Filtisaf - New Financing, 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Filtisaf - Bond Issues - Form of Agreement, 1946-1949 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Belgian Congo - Tax Issues, 1949-1951 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Filtisaf, 1956-1957 (Box 17, Folder 2-5)
  - Bicycle Tires, 1952-1953 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Trip to the Congo, 1953 May (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Bluebeard's Castle Hotel, 1953-1954 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Indussa - Pharmaceutical Products - Belgian Congo, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Indussa - Palm Oil, 1952-1953 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Indussa, 1953-1960 (Box 18, Folder 3-6)
  - Industrial Power and Explosives - Venezuela, 1952-1953 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Synthetic Fertilizers and Chemicals, 1953-1960 (Box 19, Folder 2-3)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Reports to Directors, 1953-1956 (Box 19, Folder 5-6)